so welcome back to electric vehicles
channel my dear friends i am krishna
nitin mandela in this ask electric
vehicles ninth episode i will answer
some of the subscribers questions
so firstly most of the subscribers are
confused about the subsidy part
especially the state government subsidy
and the central government subsidy so i
will clarify all your doubts so i will
start explaining about the central
government subsidy the central
government subsidy irrespective of any
state you will get the subsidy okay it
is common for all the state people but
now coming to the state government
subsidy it is based on the state
government ev policy for example as of
now only six states are providing state
government subsidy the states are delhi
gujarat maharashtra
rajasthan orissa and assam these are the
six states providing state government
subsidies whereas the central government
subsidy for example ola electric scooter
the actual room price is one lakh rupees
so that one lakh price is including the
fame to scheme subsidies but if you are
living in delhi you will get another 15
000 rupees of subsidy due to the state
government subsidy so central government
subsidy is a default subsidy
whereas state government subsidies is
based on their state government ev
policy but how to apply for this
subsidies as a customer you don't need
to apply for any subsidies the moment
you are buying an electric vehicle all
you need to provide is another card or a
palm card or the address proof like your
driving license
if you provide these proofs the dealer
themselves apply the subsidy for you and
one more important thing
the subsidy is only once per the user
for example you purchase either electric
scooter
and you cannot buy ola electric scooter
with the fame to scheme subsidy benefits
so you need to pay the full amount for
ola electric scooter in in case if you
have already purchased aether 450x with
the subsidies so at that time what you
need to do instead of your account you
can use your father's account so that
you will get the subsidies again and the
second question most of the viewers
asked about the regenerator braking
system is the regenerative braking
system affect the battery life cycles of
course it will affect the battery life
cycles even i have confirmed this same
question with the founder of reward
motors who is making the nx100 electric
scooter i asked the same question
because you are using one of the
optimized regenerative braking system in
your electric scooter so will the
regenerative braking system affect the
battery life cycles the moment you
charge your battery and you discharge
the battery it is considered as a one
life cycle so it can be through a three
pin plug or a regenerative braking
system you are charging your battery so
which means it will affect your life
cycles of the battery pack so that's the
answer for your question and the next
question is asked by mr aryan patil
let me know how much time will ola
scooter take for delivery me and my
family really need this scooter in two
months what shall i do
see already we mentioned that you need
some luck the moment the payment window
opened it purely depends on how many
stocks that olaf put for the customers
for example if they keep only thousand
units and if you are lucky enough to
done the payment part in the first
session itself and you will get the
delivery in the next two months but in
case if you miss that it is out of stock
then you need to wait for couple of
months but ola doesn't reveal so far how
many units will it keep in their flash
sale and the next question is asked by
mr shankar raja what will be the life
cycle of electric vehicle
it will be used only for three years and
it has no resale value
so it is one of the
most common doubt every user having
before buying an electric vehicle so
don't get confused with the term three
year warranty on the battery pack but
how can we estimate this battery life
cycle the lifetime of the lithium-ion
batteries can be calculated only based
on the life cycles in the current indian
eva market the average life cycles
offered by lithium-ion battery
manufacturers are 800 cycles
for example ola ether or simple one they
might offer up to thousand cycles so
take an average of 900 cycles if you are
using 20 kilometers on your electric
scooter
which means you need to charge only
seven times a week so you are spending
seven life cycles in one month
so for one year you are spending around
84 life cycles take another six cycles
so if you round figure it you will get
90 life cycles so you are consuming 90
life cycles of your battery pack in one
year so for 900 cycles you have 10 years
of lifetime if you are using your
battery vehicle only for 20 kilometers
but who need to change the battery for
three years if someone who is using the
vehicle up to 100 kilometers a day then
they need to do the charging every day
so every day they are using one life
cycle so for 365 days
they are using 365 life cycles
for two years they are spending around
760 life cycles so their lifetime will
end in two and a half years so that is
the difference between life cycles
don't get fall into this three year
warranty trap okay it's purely the life
of lithium and battery depends on the
life cycles and the next question is
asked by mr rickson
i need your suggestion i stay in
bangalore currently there are no quality
electric scooters in bangalore i have
thought of buying one from bengaluru
which is around 370 kilometers away from
bangalore if i if i buy from bengaluru
and use it in mangalore what problems do
you think i might face considering
bengaluru is 370 kilometers away so it
is one of the very important question so
we will do one separate video for this
question so because most of the viewers
having the same doubt and finally the
last question is asked by mr samuel when
will revolt comes to vizag
in vizag already revolt motor showroom
is under construction maybe within few
weeks or one month we will get an update
about revolt motor showroom in vizag so
these are some of the subscribers
questions and viewers if you have any
doubts about electric vehicles please do
ask them in the comment section below
and we will answer them in the coming
videos for general information about
electric vehicles please do subscribe
our electric vehicle channel and for
faster updates please do follow our
facebook page and website go green go
electric